[
  {
    "question": "What is an <strong>associate broker</strong>?",
    "answer": "An associate broker is a licensee who meets the educational and experience requirements to be a managing broker, but who is providing real estate services under the supervision of a managing broker."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a <strong>brokerage</strong>?",
    "answer": "A brokerage is a licensee (often corporate) on behalf of which other licensees must provide real estate services."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a <strong>disclosure statement</strong>?",
    "answer": "A disclosure statement is a document, prepared by the developer of a development property in accordance with the Real Estate Development Marketing Act, to ensure that investors or purchasers receive adequate information upon which to base a purchase of a development unit in British Columbia."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the responsibilities of a <strong>managing broker</strong>?",
    "answer": "A managing broker is responsible for exercising the rights conferred on the brokerage as well as for the performance of the duties imposed on a brokerage by its licence. In addition, a managing broker is responsible for the control and conduct of a brokerage's real estate business, including the supervision of its related licensees."
  },
  {
    "question": "A ______ account is an account in which money is deposited by one person for the ________ of another. The money is devoted to a particular purpose and _______ be diverted for other purposes.",
    "answer": "A <strong>trust</strong> account is an account in which money is deposited by one person for the <strong>benefit</strong> of another. The money is devoted to a particular purpose and <strong>cannot</strong> be diverted for other purposes."
  },
  {
    "question": "Exemptions from licensing under the Real Estate Services Act are located in the Act itself, the Regulations and the Real Estate Services Rules.<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;(2) False",
    "answer": "Exemptions from licensing under the Real Estate Services Act are located in the Act itself, the Regulations and the <em>Real Estate Services Rules.</em><br />&nbsp;<strong>(1) True</strong><br />&nbsp;(2) False"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Real Estate Errors and Omissions Insurance Corporation receives the interest payable on all brokerage trust accounts held in savings institutions except separate trust accounts maintained for specific clients.<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;(2) False",
    "answer": "&nbsp;(2) False. It is the Real Estate Foundation, not the Real Estate Errors and Omissions Insurance Corporation, that receives the interest payable on all brokerage trust accounts held in savings institutions except separate trust accounts maintained for specific clients."
  },
  {
    "question": "As soon as a developer becomes aware of the fact that a _________ ________ does not comply with the Real Estate Development Marketing Act (\"REDMA\") or the REDMA Regulation, or contains a misrepresentation, the developer must file and deliver a new or amended one.",
    "answer": "As soon as a developer becomes aware of the fact that a <strong>disclosure statement</strong> does not comply with the Real Estate Development Marketing Act (\"REDMA\") or the REDMA Regulation, or contains a misrepresentation, the developer must file and deliver a new or amended one."
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the two broad categories of improper conduct by licensees that are set out in the Real Estate Services Act.",
    "answer": "The Real Estate Services Act sets out two broad categories of improper conduct by licensees: professional misconduct and conduct unbecoming a licensee."
  },
  {
    "question": "_______ _______ is defined as activities related to the purchase and sale of real estate, including transactions for the leasing of real estate and assignments of contracts for purchase, sale, and lease of real estate.",
    "answer": "<strong>Trading services</strong> is defined as activities related to the purchase and sale of real estate, including transactions for the leasing of real estate and assignments of contracts for purchase, sale, and lease of real estate."
  },
  {
    "question": "_____ is a relationship in which one person (the ____) is authorized by another person (the ____) to act on their behalf in dealing with third parties.",
    "answer": "<strong>Agency</strong> is a relationship in which one person (the <strong>agent</strong>) is authorized by another person (the <strong>principal</strong>) to act on their behalf in dealing with third parties."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a listing contract?",
    "answer": "A listing contract is a written service agreement where the brokerage contracts to provide trading services to an owner of real estate in relation to the offering of the real estate for sale."
  },
  {
    "question": "A(n) _______ _________ is held in a bank, trust company, or credit union in which a third party (the _______) holds all money received for or on behalf of a client (the ________).",
    "answer": "A(n) <strong>trust account</strong> is held in a bank, trust company, or credit union in which a third party (the <strong>trustee</strong>) holds all money received for or on behalf of a client (the <strong>beneficiary</strong>)."
  },
  {
    "question": "A _______ is a person authorized to exercise all of the powers necessary to wind up the business and affairs of a licensee.",
    "answer": "A <strong>receiver</strong> is a person authorized to exercise all of the powers necessary to wind up the business and affairs of a licensee.<strong>receiver</strong>"
  },
  {
    "question": "Unlicensed assistants are permitted to perform trading services if they are supervised by a broker.<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;(2) False",
    "answer": "Unlicensed assistants are permitted to perform trading services if they are supervised by a broker.<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;<strong>(2) False</strong>"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which act governs the sale of real estate in British Columbia?",
    "answer": "The Real Estate Services Act (RESA)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which regulatory agency is responsible for making the Real Estate Services Rules and appointing the Superintendent of Real Estate?",
    "answer": "The BC Financial Services Authority"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the Real Estate Errors and Omissions Insurance Corporation?",
    "answer": "The Real Estate Errors and Omissions Insurance Corporation is a statutorily created corporation that provides an affordable method of protecting licensees from financial loss due to errors and omissions."
  },
  {
    "question": "What purpose does the Real Estate Special Compensation Fund serve?",
    "answer": "The Real Estate Special Compensation Fund provides compensation to persons in relation to a real estate transaction for funds that were misappropriated, or intentionally not paid or accounted for by licensees, officers or directors, employees, or independent contractors of a brokerage."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a development unit?",
    "answer": "In the context of the Real Estate Development Marketing Act, a development unit is a subdivision lot, bare land strata lot, strata lot, cooperative interest, time share interest, shared interest in land, or a leasehold interest (provided they are located in a development property)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Describe a managing broker.",
    "answer": "A managing broker is a licensed individual in a brokerage who is responsible for the supervision of the brokerageâ€™s licensees and who must be actively engaged in the management of the brokerage to ensure compliance with relevant statutes, regulations, and bylaws."
  },
  {
    "question": "Improper conduct encompasses both professional misconduct and conduct unbecoming a licensee.<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;(2) False",
    "answer": "Improper conduct encompasses both professional misconduct and conduct unbecoming a licensee.<br />&nbsp;<strong>(1) True</strong><br />&nbsp;(2) False"
  },
  {
    "question": "Conduct that is contrary to the best interests of the public, undermines public confidence in the real estate industry, or brings the real estate industry into disrepute is known as:",
    "answer": "conduct unbecoming a licensee."
  },
  {
    "question": "The BC Financial Services Authority and a licensee can agree to a ____ ____, forgoing the need for a full discipline hearing.",
    "answer": "The BC Financial Services Authority and a licensee can agree to a <strong>consent order</strong>, forgoing the need for a full discipline hearing."
  },
  {
    "question": "Administrative penalties imposed by the Superintendent of Real Estate are typically more onerous than those set out in the Real Estate Services Act.<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;(2) False",
    "answer": "Administrative penalties imposed by the Superintendent of Real Estate are typically more onerous than those set out in the Real Estate Services Act.<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;<strong>(2) False</strong><br />Administrative penalties are typically less onerous than those set out in the Real Estate Services Act."
  }
]